http://www.georgianc.on.ca/privacy-policy/

Accept your offer
Confirm your seat (pay your deposit)
First year experience
Head start (pre-orientation)
Georgian College privacy statement
Georgian is committed to respecting your privacy and protecting your personal information. In accordance with Section 39(2) of the Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act, R.S.O. 1990, c. F.31, this is to advise you that your personal information is collected under the legal authority of the Ontario Colleges of Applied Arts and Technology Act, 2002. This information may be used and/or disclosed for administrative, statistical and/or research purposes of the college and/or ministries and agencies of the government of Ontario and the government of Canada, including, but not limited to, tabulating and reporting data on Key Performance Indicators (graduation rate, graduate employment, graduate satisfaction and employer satisfaction).
You may also be contacted by ministry or college-authorized third parties for your voluntary participation in surveys to evaluate student and graduate experiences and outcomes. Information will also be shared with third party service providers who are retained by the college to provide services to students or act as agents of the college (working in accordance with privacy guidelines).
Georgian College is required to disclose personal information such as Ontario education numbers, student characteristics and educational outcomes to the Minister of Advanced Education and Skills Development under s. 15 of the Ministry of Training, Colleges and Universities Act, R.S.O. 1990, Chapter M.19, as amended. The Ministry collects this data for purposes such as planning, allocating and administering public funding to colleges, universities and other postsecondary educational and training institutions and to conduct research and analysis, including longitudinal studies, and statistical activities conducted by or on behalf of the Ministry for purposes that relate to postsecondary education and training. Further information on how the Minister of Advanced Education and Skills Development uses this personal information is available at: http://www.tcu.gov.on.ca/eng/employmentontario/personalinfo.html.
Further information on the collection and use of student-level enrolment-related data can be obtained from the Ministry of Advanced Education and Skills Development website: http://www.tcu.gov.on.ca/ or by writing to the Director, Postsecondary Finance Branch, Postsecondary Education Division, 7th Floor, Mowat Block, 900 Bay Street, Toronto, ON M7A 1L2. By consenting, you are authorizing Georgian to use your personal information for processing your application, acceptance or registration as well as taxation, student insurance or funding purposes.
Georgian College Privacy Policy (PDF)
Statistics Canada Notice
Notification of disclosure of personal information to Statistics CanadaStatistics Canada is the national statistical agency. As such, Statistics Canada carries out hundreds of surveys each year on a wide range of matters, including education.
It is essential to be able to follow students across time and institutions to understand, forexample, the factors affecting enrolment demand at postsecondary institutions. The increased emphasis on accountability for public investment means that it is also importantto understand ‘outcomes’. In order to conduct such studies, Statistics Canada asks allcolleges and universities to provide data on students and graduates. Institutions collect and provide to Statistics Canada, student identification information (student’s name, student ID number, Social Insurance Number), student contact information (address and telephone number), student demographic characteristics, enrolment information, previous education,and labour force activity.
The federal Statistics Act provides the legal authority for Statistics Canada to obtain access to personal information held by educational institutions. The information may be used for statistical purposes only, and the confidentiality provisions of the Statistics Act prevent the information from being released in any way that would identify a student.
Students who do not wish to have their information used can ask Statistics Canada to remove their identifying information from the national database. On request by a student,Statistics Canada will delete an individual’s contact information (name, address, or otherpersonal identifiers) from the PSIS database. To make such a request, please contact us:
Via telephone:
Monday to Friday
8:30 a.m.. to 4:30 p.m.EST/EDST
1.800.307.3382 or
1.613.951.7608
Via mail:
Institutional Surveys Section
Centre for Education Statistics
Statistics Canada, Main Building, SC 2100-K
Tunney’s Pasture, Ottawa, ON K1A 0T6
Via email:
PSIS-SIEP_contact@statcan.gc.ca
Statistics Canada maintains a recommended standard disclosure notice for reporting toStatistics Canada’s Postsecondary Student Information System (PSIS) on the PSISWebsite at:
www23.statcan.gc.ca/
For further information about use, collection, retention and disposal of personal information at Georgian College, please contact:
Access and Privacy Office
705.728.1968, ext. 5770
accessprivacy@georgiancollege.ca
Protection of personal health information
Georgian College is committed to respecting your privacy and protecting your personal health information in compliance with the Personal Health Information Protection Act, 2004 (PHIPA). PHIPA establishes rules for the collection, use and disclosure of personal health information (PHI), in order to protect the confidentiality and privacy of individuals with respect to that information while also facilitating the effective provision of health care. PHIPA also provides individuals with the right to access their PHI and correct or amend their PHI.
Students and members of the public accessing services in Georgian College’s clinical and wellness services may be asked to provide personal and personal health information, and personal health information may be collected and maintained as part of its service delivery practices.
For more information and a full list of services available in the Georgian College clinics, please view the Community and Alumni tab on the college home page.
For more information concerning the collection, use and disclosure of personal health information (PHI) at Georgian College, contact:
Access and Privacy Office
705.728.1968, ext. 5770
accessprivacy@georgiancollege.ca
Access, corrections and Freedom of Information
In addition to the right of individuals to access and correct their own personal information (PI) and personal health information (PHI), FIPPA also provides for Freedom of Information (FOI) allowing the general public access to records held by public institutions barring exemptions listed in the Act (e.g., cabinet records, third party information, etc.).
To request access or correction to your PI or PHI, or make a Freedom of Information (FOI) request, please complete the following form that includes instructions and also indicates any fees associated with processing your request(s):
Request for access to or correction of personal information/personal health information or Freedom of Information Request
Please submit your completed form, with the application fee, to:
ATTN: Access and Privacy Office, C301
Georgian College
One Georgian Drive
Barrie, ON L4M 3X9
In order to process your request, an original signature is required from the requestor.
For further information about use, collection, retention and disposal of personal or personal health information at Georgian College, please contact:
